supply and demand the concept at the
very core of the financial markets
mastering this will allow you to take
great trades consistently and build a
thriving career in trading so cut off
all distractions in the next 10 minutes
I'm going to show you everything you
need to know to master supply and demand
trading what is supply and demand Supply
refers to the amount of sellers in a
market and demand refers to the amount
of buyers market prices are driven by
the battle between buyers and sellers
when there's more selling than buying
High Supply than the markets move lower
and when there's more buying than
selling high demand then markets move
higher the battle between supply and
demand is quite literally why the
markets move with good news and positive
developments for a currency more people
want to buy and as a result there's more
demand and market prices go up the same
is true for bad news where Traders react
by selling off the assets that they have
and by losing interest in buying more
this results in an increase in Supply
and a decrease in demand and as a result
the markets fall lower on paper this
isn't an interesting concept but how
exactly can you use it on the charts to
improve your trading results by reading
the supply and demand of a market in
real time using zones to find a supply
or demand Zone we want to identify an
area of consolidation sideways price
action before a large up or down move a
demand zone is a consolidation before a
big upward move and a supply zone is
consolidation before a big downward move
these zones are areas where large
amounts of buying or selling has taken
place in the past and they can be used
to take high probability High reward
trades in the future here's an example
by looking at this chart we can clearly
see there was a demand Zone here which
was an area where a large amount of
buying took place we know that Traders
see this price as a discounted price to
buy this asset so we can then assume if
the market returns to this price once
again Traders will be happy to buy here
again because it's a fair price to
purchase contracts at so what we would
do is avoid buying until price hits the
zone and then focus our efforts on
securing an entry inside of the demand
Zone stop losses would simply be placed
below the zone and if the Zone doesn't
hold it tells us the market is reversing
and the best thing we can do in that
scenario is cut the loss short and get
out the same Theory applies to supply
zones but instead of looking to buy we
would look to sell now this is important
so listen up when you look at a chart
you'll realize there are seemingly
supply and demand zones everywhere at
the top and bottom of every single move
you're going to see a small
consolidation obviously buying or
selling a retest of every single zone is
not going to work out well you'll take a
massive amount of losses and explode
your trading account very quickly so to
avoid that we want to make sure we're
always trading with the trend so when a
market is trending up we should focus on
buying demand zones and totally ignore
Supply zones and when a market is
trending down we should sell from Supply
zones and ignore the demand zones that
form within the trend and to determine
the direction of a trend we can just
read the highs and lows in price action
a market that is consistently forming
higher highs and higher lows is in an
uptrend and a market that is
consistently forming lower lows and
lower highs is in a downtrend if you
need to learn more about Market
structure click the card in the top
corner of this video to watch my class
about that concept buy demand in
uptrends and sell Supply in downtrends
and if you break this all important rule
you will go broke fast so don't forget
it another important thing to note is
that supply and demand zones are only
good one time when a Zone has been
retested once it is written off so if
the retest results in a huge move
awesome but if the market slumps back
down and hits the Zone a second or third
time it shows us that the buying is not
as strong as anticipated and it's likely
that the Zone will break instead of
holding up so only consider buying or
selling from demand zones or Supply
zones that haven't been retested yet if
a Zone has already been hit don't go
buying on a second or third tap it won't
work out well for you so now you know
how to find supply and demand zones and
how to use them for getting into trades
you also know you should be trading them
with the trend but supply and demand has
another use too targets we can use open
Supply and demand zones as targets for
the trades that we take and to explain
this it's best to just show you an
example so for this example trade we're
looking at a buy from this demand Zone
in this predominant uptrend now we can
use supply and demand zones as targets
and this is how we do it obviously if we
know we're in an uptrend we want to only
buy from demand that is what we're going
to focus on however if we're expecting
the market to go up we can actually use
a supply Zone as a safe Target for our
trade now we could use this one here we
have this imbalanced range we have this
clear Supply at the top and we know that
with the market reversal it's likely we
get to this point however these smaller
range in price action is actually
bearish at the moment so the big picture
is bullish but this smaller picture is
bearish meaning we know this Supply Zone
could potentially form a reaction when
we get to it so what we could do is use
this Supply as the target for our trade
get out and then assess what the market
does later and as you can see after
reacting from this Supply we did have
quite a lot large bearish move so it's
often a good idea to use Supply zones as
targets for buys when you're buying from
demand and on the flip side if you're
using Supply to sell the market demand
zones can be a very good place to Target
to get out of your trade safely before
Market reversals to round off this class
I want to show you a trade I took from
start to finish using the concept of
supply and demand so that you can see
how all the elements I've covered so far
come together so for this example trade
we're going to look at quite an old
trade from 2023 but this is a really
clear simple example and a great first
introduction to the concept of supply
and demand so what we have is a
predominant uptrend in the market and
then we saw the market reverse and trade
down towards this demand Zone just here
so now we have an uptrend and we know we
want to buy from demand and ignore
Supply zones for the most part because
we are trending upwards now after this
retest we had a push-up we had a break
of structure and we left open at this
low another demand Zone you can see it's
a consolidation move before the upward
move and also consol idation can be seen
as we see here in individual candles as
kind of consolidation candles with large
Wicks that show essentially a lower time
frame
consolidation so what we can do now is
look for a buy from this demand because
we have a clear demand Zone in a clear
uptrend as we covered before we can put
our stop- loss under the low and then
for targets what could we target well we
could Target the supply Zone at the top
of this move this Supply zone is very
likely to be filled considering we're in
an uptrend and if it does form a
reaction we will be able to secure over
10% in profits from where we are here
all the way up to this Supply zone so we
can place an order just here and then we
can allow the market to play out and as
you will see this trade was filled very
precisely from the demand and then we
had a very nice quick upward move all
the way towards that Supply zone so I
took this trade and I made around 11% on
this and yes it's an old trade but the
concept stand true and I'm showing you
this one because it's a very clean
example for your first introduction to
supply and demand and there you have you
have it supply and demand the concept at
the very heart of the market and the
strategies that you can use to
successfully trade with supply and
demand at the core of your strategy it's
simple effective and grounded in logic
and it's a concept that will never get
old or die because the endless battle
between buyers and selling between
demand and Supply is literally why the
markets move now if you enjoyed that hit
the link in the description and you'll
be taken to my free course it's going to
break down 10 reasons why you're not
winning and how you can turn your
results around and by the way depending
when you're watching this video I have a
50% promo on my trading Mastermind so if
you want to get a full comprehensive
education and work with me to put your
strategies into action in the markets
every day then hit the Mastermind Link
in the description and join us on the
inside now get to work on breaking down
supply and demand in the markets I hope
it brings the same success to you that
it brought to me that's all from me I
see you in the next
video